In the last two segments we talked about
the CBC-MAC and NMAC to convert a PRF for
过去的两小节中我们讨论过使用CBC-MAC和NMAC将
small messages into a PRF for much larger
messages. Those two constructions were
供短消息使用的PRF转换为供长消息使用的PRF 这两种构造方法都是
sequential, in the sense that if you had
multiple processors you couldn't make the
时序的 意思是 即便你有多处理器 你仍然不能
construction work any faster. In this
segment we're gonna look at a parallel MAC
加快这种构造的工作效率 本节 我们将学习一种平行MAC
that also converts a small PRF into a
large PRF, but does it in a very
它也能将小型PRF转成大型PRF 但它是否是
parallelizable fashion. In particular we're
gonna look at a parallel MAC construction
平行模式呢 特别地 我们将学习一种叫做PMAC的平行MAC结构
called PMAC, that uses an underlying PRF
to construct a PRF for much larger
它可以用一个基本PRF来构建一个供更长消息使用的PRF
messages. In particular, the PRF can
process much longer messages that can have
更特别地 这个PRF可以处理变长和
variable length and have as many as L
blocks in them. Now the construction works
具有与L块相同数量的消息 这个结构的工作方式如下
as follows. We take our message and we
break it into blocks. And then we process
我们得到消息并分块 之后逐个处理块
each block independently of the other. So,
the first thing we do, is we evaluate some
所以 首先要做的是 求函数
function P and we XOR the result
into the first message block, and then we
P的值 然后将这个值与第一个消息值异或 接着
apply our function F using a key k1.
We do the same for each one of the
将得到值送入函数F并用密钥K1 我们为每个消息块做相同的操作
message blocks and you notice that we can
do it all parallel, all message blocks are
你应该注意到 我们可以平行地完成这个步骤 所有消息块
processed independently of one another.
And we collect all these results into some
都是独立地被处理的 然后 我们收集得到的所有结果并送入
final XOR and then we encrypt one more time
to get the final tag value. Now for a
最终异或计算器 接着我们再加密一次从而得到最终的标记值
technical reason, actually on the very
last one. We actually don't need to apply
由于技术的原理 最后一个 我们不必使用
the PRF F, but as I said, this is just
for technical reason, and I'm going to
PRF F 但正如我所说 这只是因为技术原因 我打算忽视这个问题
ignore that for now. Now, I want to
explain what the function P is for and
现在我想解释函数P是为了什么 并且
what it does. So imagine, just for a
second, that the function P isn't actually
它是用来干什么的 这里假设 函数P并不存在
there. That is, imagine we actually,
directly feed each message block into the
那么实际上 我们将直接将每个消息块送入
PRF without applying any other
processing to it. Then I claim that the
PRF 而没有使用其它任何处理 所以我说
resulting MAC is completely insecure and
the reason is essentially no order is
作为结果的MAC是完全不安全的 因为本质上
enforced between the message blocks. In
particular, if I swap two message blocks,
消息块之间没有执行任何操作 特别地 假设我交换两消息块位置
that doesn't change the value of the final
tag. Because the XOR is commutative, the
将不会改变最终特征值 由于XOR是或交换的 所以特征值
tag will be the same whether we swap the
blocks or not. As a result, an attacker
不会改变 不管我们交换消息块位置与否 就结果来说
can request the tag for a particular
message, and then he obtains the tag for a
攻击者为一消息请求特征值 他交换两消息块 并得到这一消息的特征值
message where two of the blocks are
swapped and that counts as an existential
这可算做一种伪造
forgery. So what this function P tries to
do is essentially enforce order on these
所以这个函数P所做的是为这些消息块执行命令操作
blocks. And you notice that the function
takes, first of all, it's a keyed function,
注意到 首先这个函数是键控函数
so it takes a key as input. And second of
all, more importantly, it takes the block
所以他需要一个密钥做为输入 更重要的第二点 它接收消息块号做为输入
number as input. In other words, the
value of the function is different for
换言之 每块的函数值是不同的
each one of the blocks. And that's
actually exactly what's preventing this,
所以 正是这个属性可以防止这种
blocks swapping attack. So the function P
actually, is a very easy to compute
消息块交换攻击 所以函数P 计算起来很容易
function. Essentially given the key and
the message block, all it is, is just a
基本上 给定密钥与消息块 所需的只是
multiplication in some finite fields. So
it's a very, very simple function to
有限域内的乘法 所以它是个非常容易计算的函数
compute. It adds very little to the
running time of PMAC. And yet, it's
它对于PMAC来说只会增加非常少的时间 与之相反的是
enough in ensure that the PMAC is
actually secure. As we've said, the key
它可确保PAMC是安全的 正如前面所说 PAMC的密钥
for PMAC is this pair of keys. One key for
the PRF, and one key for this masking
是这对密钥 一个供PRF使用 一个供函数掩模P使用
function P. And finally, I'll tell you
that if the message length is not a
最后 我需要阐述一点如果消息长度不是
multiple of the block length. That is,
imagine the last block is shorter than
块长度的整数倍 也就是 如果最后一个消息块短于一个整块
full block length, then PMAC actually uses
a padding that's similar to CMAC, so that
那么PMAC就会使用一个与CMAC相似的补丁 因此
there is no need for an additional dummy
block, ever. So that's the PMAC
根本没有必要增加一个傀儡块 这就是
construction and as usual, we can state
its security theorem. So the security
PMAC结构 照例 我们可以陈述它的安全理论
theorem, by now, you should be used to it.
Essentially, it says that if you give me
现在你应该已经习惯于安全理论 本质上 这个公式是说 如果有一
an adversary attacking PMAC, I can
construct an adversary attacking the
正在攻击PMAC的敌手 那么我可以构建一正在攻击基础PRF的敌手
underlying PRF. Plus an additional error
term. And so, since again, the PRF is
再加上误差项 这里PRF
secure, we know that this term is
negligible. And so if we want this term to
是安全的 我们知道该项是可忽略的 所以如果我想让该项也是
be negligible, we know that, we need this
error term to also be negligible. Here, as
可忽略的 我们应该知道 我们需要让误差项变得可忽略
usual, q is the number of messages that
are MAC-ed using a particular key. And L
照例 Q是使用一特殊密钥计算的消息的杂凑值
is the maximum length of all those
messages. And PMAC is secure, as long as
L是这些消息的最大长度 并且PMAC是安全的 只要
its product is less than the square root
of the block size. So for AES this would be
这个乘积小于块大小的平方根 对AES来说 这个块大小为2^128
two to the 128, and the square root,
therefore, would be two to the 64th. So the
所以平方根是2^64
MAC would be secure, as long as Q times L
is less than two to the 64th. And every time,
所以这个MAC算法是安全的条件是 Q*L的值小于2^64 并且每当
as it gets closer to that value, of
course, you would have to change the key
积值越接近2^64 你就必须改变密钥
in order to continue MAC-ing more
messages. So the main thing to remember is
来计算更多消息的杂凑值 所以主要要记住
that PMAC also gives us a PRF, and when it
processes the message blocks independently
当PMAC逐条处理消息时 PMAC也可相当于PRF
of one another. Turns out that PMAC also
has a very interesting property. Namely,
事实上PMAC有一个非常有意思的属性 即
that PMAC math is incremental. So let me
explain to you what that means. So suppose
PMAC算法是增值的 这里让我解释下它的意思 假设
the function F that's used to construct PMAC
is not just a PRF, but, in fact, a
PMAC结构中所用的函数F并不仅仅是一个PRF 而是一个置换
permutation, PRP. So we can actually
invert it when we need to. Now suppose
PRP 所以如果需要 我们可以将其逆转 现假设
we've already computed the MAC for a
particularly long message m. And now,
我们已计算过消息m的杂凑值 接着
suppose just one message block of this
long message changes. So here, m[1] has
假设该长消息中一消息换被改变 假定m[1]→m＇[1]
changed into m'[1]. But the
remaining message blocks all remain the
但剩余的消息块保持原样
same. For other MAC-s, like CBC-MAC, even
though only one message block changed, you
对于其它杂凑算法 如CBC-MAC来说 即便仅改变一消息块
would have to recompute the tag on the
entire message. Recomputing the tag
还是需要重新计算整个消息的特征值 重新计算特征值
basically will take time that's
proportional to the length of the message.
会依消息长度成比例消耗更多时间
It turns out, with PMAC, if we only
change one block, or a small number of
事实上 对于PMAC 如果我们仅改变一消息块 或少量消息块
blocks, actually, we can recompute the
value of the tag for the new message very,
我们可以非常快地为新消息重新计算特征值
very quickly. And let me ask you a puzzle
to see if you can figure out how to do
这里我为你们提一个疑问 来看看你们自己能否想出快速计算的方法
that yourself. And remember, the function
F is a PRP, and therefore is invertible.
记住 函数F是一个PRP 因此它是可逆的
So let's see if you can figure out how to
compute the MAC in the new message by
让我们看看能不能快速完成新消息杂凑值的计算
yourself. So it turns out this can be
done. And you can quickly recompute the
事实上 是可以完成的 可以快速重计算新消息的新特征值
tag on the new message using this third
line here. Just to make sure we all see
只需要使用这里写的三条公式 为了确保大家都能明白
the solution let's quickly go back to the
original diagram for PMAC and I can show
这个解决办法 让我们回到前面讲过的PMAC的原理图 然后我会说明
you what I mean. So imagine this one
message block changed into some other
解决办法 假想这个消息块变成另一消息块
block, say, it changed into M'[1]. Then
what we could do is we can take the tag on
如变成m＇[1] 接下来我们要做的是 获取改变
the original message before the change was
made. So we can invert the function F, and
之前的消息特征值 并且逆转函数F
determine the value before the function F
was applied. Now, well, since we now have
再利用逆转后F确定使用函数F之前的值 这个值是
an XOR of a bunch of blocks, what
we can do is we can cancel out the XOR
一群消息块的异或值 之后我们可以抵消
that came from the original message block,
basically by XOR-ing this value that came
原始块m[1]的异或 方法是将原始消息中的这个值
from the original message block into this
XOR-ed accumulator. And then XOR-ing again
与刚才得到的所有原始消息异或值进行异或  接着再次将新消息
the value that would come from the new
message block back into the XOR
中的这个值与抵消后的异或值进行异或
accumulator. And then apply the function F
again. And that will give us the tag for
接着使用函数F 这样就得到了新消息的特征值
the new message, where just one block was
changed. So in symbols, basically, I wrote
而且新消息中仅有一消息块被改变
the formula over here. You can see,
basically, we decrypt the tag, and then we
这里 我写出了流程工式 你们能看到 我们解密特征值 然后
XOR with the block that comes from the
original message block. We XOR again with
将得到的值与由原始消息块得到的块异或 接着再将得到的值与
the block that comes from the new message
block. And then we re-encrypt the final
由新消息块得到的消息块异或 然后我们重新加密最终
XOR accumulator to get the new tag for the
message with a one block changed. So
异或累加来得到改变一消息块的新消息的特征值
that's kind of a neat property. It kind of
shows that if you have very large
整个流程很整齐 也就是说如果你有一很长
messages, you can very quickly update the
tag. Of course you would need the secret
的消息 你能快速更新特征值 当然你可以利用私密钥来
key to do the update, but you can quickly
update the tag if just a small number of
完成更新 但如果仅一小部分消息块改变了 你能用上述方法快速更新特征值
message blocks changed. Okay, so that
concludes our discussion of PMAC. And now
这也就是我们所有要讨论的PMAC 现在
I wanna switch topics a little bit, and
talk about the concept of a one time MAC,
我想转换下话题 来说说一次性MAC的概念
which is basically the analog of the one
time pad, but in the world of integrity.
它除在完整性算法中 均与一次性密码本相似
So let me explain what I mean by that. So
imagine we wanna build a MAC that is only
这里让我解释下我想表达的意思 假想我们想构建一个MAC 且它
used for integrity of a single message. In
other words, every time we compute the
仅能为单条消息的完整性算法使用 换言 每当我们计算
integrity of a particular message, we also
change the key. So that any particular key
特定消息的完整性时 我们会改变密钥 所以任何特定密钥
is used only for integrity of one message.
Then we can define the security game as
仅供单条消息使用 接着我们可以由攻击者只能看到单条消息来
basically saying, the attacker's gonna see
one message. Therefore, we only allow him
定义安全性的测试方法 因此 我们只让攻击者攻击
to do one chosen message attack. So he
gets to submit one message query, and he
选定的单条消息 所以他会提交一条消息请求
is given the tag corresponding to that one
message query. And now his goal is to
接着他会得到请求消息的响应特征值 攻击者目标是
forge a message tag pair. Okay, so you
can see his goal was to produce one
伪造消息特征值对 你可以看到他的止标是产生一个
message tag pair that verifies correctly and
is different from the pair that he was
可以正确认证并与给定的对不相同的消息特征值对
actually given. As we'll see, just like
the one time pad and stream ciphers were
我们将看到 正如一次性密码本与流密码非常
quite useful, it turns out one time MAC-s
are also quite useful for the same
有用一样 事实上 对于一次性MAC来说
applications when we only wanna use a key
to encrypt or to provide integrity for
当我们仅想用一密钥来为单条消息加密或提供完整性时 它是非常有用的
just a single message. So as usual we
would say that a one time act is secure,
所以照例 我们会说一次性的举动是安全的
because basically no adversary can win
this game. Now the interesting thing is
因为 基本上没有攻击者可以赢得这场比赛 这里有趣的事是
that one time MAC-s, just like the one time
pad can be secure against infinitely
一次性MAC 与一次性密码本一样 非常安全 并可抵御无限
powerful adversaries. And not only that,
because they're only designed to be secure
强大的攻击者们 不仅如此 因为这些MAC仅对于
for one time use, they can actually be
faster than MAC-s that are based on PRFs.
一次性使用来说是安全的 所以事实上一次性MACs 可以比以PRF为基础的MAC快
And so I just wanted to give you a quick
example of one one time MAC, this is a
这些我想给你们举一个一次性MAC的例子 这是一个
classic construction for a one time MAC,
let me show you how it works. The first
一次性MAC的经典结构 我会展示它的工作方式 首先
step is to pick a prime that's slightly
larger than our block size. In this case
选定一个稍大于块大小的素数 本例中
we're going to use 128-bit blocks, so
let's pick the first prime that's bigger
我们使用的是128bit块 所以我们选择第一个
than two to the 128th. This happens to be
two to the 128th plus 51. And now the key
大于2^128的素数 这正好是2^128+51 接着密钥是从
is going to be a pair of random numbers in
the range 1 to our prime, so 1 to q. So we
1到选定素数中的随机数对 即1―q
choose two random integers in the range 1
to q. Now we're given a message so we're
所以我们从1-q中选两个随机整数 接着给定一个消息
going to take our message and break it
into blocks where each block is 128 bits,
我们将该消息分块 每块大小128bits
and we're going to regard each number as
an integer in the range 0 to 2 to the
并且块中的每个数字是0-(2^128-1)中的任一整数
128th minus 1. Now the MAC is defined as
follows. The first thing we do is we take
这里MAC的定义如下 首先要做的是获取
our message blocks and we kind of
construct the polynomial out of them. So
消息块然后依这些消息块构建一类多项式
if there are L blocks in our message,
we're going to construct the polynomial of
所以如果消息有L块 我们将构建L次多项式
degree L and you notice that the constant
term of the polynomial is set to zero. And
注意到多项式的常数项设为0
then we define the MAC very simply.
Basically what we do is we take the
之后MAC的定就非常简单了 基本上我们得到
polynomial that corresponds to the
message, we evaluate it at the point K
与消息对应的多项式 接着计算多项式取K时的值
that's one half of our secret key, and
then we add the value A which is the
K是密钥的一半 然后再加上值A A是
second half of our secret key. And that's
it. That's the whole MAC. So just
另一半密钥 这就是整个MAC 所以
basically construct the polynomial that
corresponds to our message, evaluate that
基本上只要构建与消息对应的多项多 计算定义域取
polynomial at half of the secret key, and
add the other half of the secret key to
密钥的一半时的值 再加上密钥的另一半
the result, and of course reduce final
result modulo q. Okay so that's it, so
当然还要对最后结果取模q 之后得到的就是
the whole MAC, it's a one time secure MAC
and we will argue that this MAC is one
完整的MAC 这就是一次性安全MAC 之后我们会讨论这个MAC是否是一次性
time secure, essentially by arguing that
if I tell you the value of MAC for one
安全的 本质上 通过讨论可以知道 假定给定一特定消息的MAC值
particular message, that tells you nothing
at all about the value of the MAC at
它不能给你关于另一消息MAC值的任何信息
another message. And as a result, even
though you've seen the value of the MAC on
结果就是 即使你已得到一特定消息的MAC值
a particular message, you have no way of
forging this MAC on some other message.
你依然没有办法伪造另一消息的MAC值
Now I should emphasize that this is a one
time MAC, but it's not two time secure. In
这里我应该强调这是一次性MAC 不能保证二次使用的安全性
other words, if you get to see the value
of the MAC on two different messages, that
换言之 如果你得到两不同消息的MAC值
actually completely compromises the
secret key. And you can actually predict a MAC
那么这肯定会危害密钥 并且你真的可以预测
for a third or fourth message of your
choice. So then the MAC becomes forgeable.
依你选择 第三 或第四条消息的MAC值 这时 MAC就变的可伪造了
But for one time use, it is a perfectly
secure MAC, and I'll tell you that in fact
但对一次性使用来说 它是完全保密的MAC 并且
it's a very fast MAC to evaluate. So now
that we've constructed one time MAC-s,
它是一种可快速评估的算法 假定我们已经构建了一定次MAC
turns out there's actually a general
technique that will convert one time MAC-s
但有一种通用技术可将一次性MAC转化成
into many time MAC-s. And I just wanted to
briefly show you how that works. So
多次性MAC 我想简单演示下它的工作方式
suppose we have our one time MAC, let's
call it S and V for signing and
假定我们有一次性MAC （S，V)且该MAC用于签名和
verification algorithms, and let's just
assume that the tags themselves are n bit
认证算法 再假设特征值是n比特串
strings. In addition, let's also look at a
PRF, a secure PRF, that also happens to
此外 我们再看看PRF 这个安全的PRF 它正好
output n bit strings but also takes as
inputs n bit strings. So let's now define
输出n比特串 且输入也为n比特串 所以这里我们定义
a general construction for a MAC. These
MAC-s are called Carter-Wegman MAC-s that
一个MAC的通用结构 这种MAC叫做Carter-Wegman MAC
works as follows. Basically what we would
do is we would apply the one time MAC to
它的工作方式如下 基本上就是我们对消息M使用一次性MAC
the message M and then we're going to
encrypt the results using the PRF. So how do
接着再用PRF对输出结果进行加密 这里我们怎样加密这个
we encrypt the result? Well, we choose a
random r and then we compute kind of a
输出结果呢 方式是选一个随机数r 接着
one time path from this r by applying the
PRF to it. And then we XOR the result
使用r与PRF进行类似于一次性密码本的加密算法 然后我们将该结果与
with the actual one time MAC. So the neat
thing about this construction is that the
前面的一次性MAC结果进行异或 这个结构的利落之处是
fast one time MAC is applied to the long
message, which could be gigabytes long.
快速一次性MAC被用在了可能是千兆字节长的长消息上
And the slower PRF is only applied to this
nonce r, which is then used to
而较慢的PRF则被于用这个临时r r被用于
encrypt the final results of the MAC. And
you can argue that if the MAC that was
加密整个MAC的最终结果 这里你可以疑惑
given to us as a building block is a one
time secure MAC, and the PRF is secure,
给定的基础MAC是否是安全的 PRF是否是安全的
then, in fact, we get a many time secure
MAC that happens to output 2n bit tags.
若都是 则我们可以得到输出2n比特特征值的一个多次性MAC
So we're gonna see Carter-Wegman MAC-s later
on when we talk about authenticated
我们会在接下来讨论认证加密时学习Carter-Wegman
encryption. And, in fact, one of the NIST standard
methods for doing encryption with
事实上 NIST完整性加密标准中的一个
integrity, uses a Carter-Wegman MAC for
providing integrity. I want to mention
正是用了carter-wegman来提供完整性 我还想补充
that this Carter-Wegman MAC is a good
example of a randomized MAC where this nonce
Carter-wegman MAC是随机MAC的一个很好的例子 且每次计算特征值时
r is chosen afresh every time the tag is
computed. And so for example if you try to
会重新选择临时r  例如 你试图
compute a tag for the same message twice
each time you'll choose a different r and
为同一次消息计算两次特征值 且选择的是不同的r 那么
as a result you'll get different tags both
times. And so this is a nice example of a
结果你会得到一对不同的特征值 所以这是一个关于MAC的很好的例子
MAC that's actually not a pseudo random
function, not a PRF, because a single
且该MAC并不是伪随机函数，即不是PRF 因为单一消息
message could actually be mapped to many
different tags all of which are valid for
可以映射到许多不同的特征值上 且它们对于该消息都是有效的
that one message. To conclude our
discussion on the Carter-Wegman MAC, let me
为了总结关于Carter-Wegman MAC的讨论 让我
ask you the following question. Here we
have the equation for the Carter-Wegman
问你接下来的这个问题 这是个关于Carter-wegman MAC的问题
MAC. As usual, you see the nonce r as
part of the MAC. And the second part of
照例 你能看到作为MAC一部分的临时r 和MAC的第二部分
the MAC I'm gonna denote by t. This is
basically the one time MAC applied to the
我以t表示这个部分 这个基本上是用于消息M的一次性MAC
message M, and then encrypted using the
pseudo-random function applied to the
接着是 使用临时r 伪随机函数加密的这部分
nonce r. So we'll denote the result of
this XOR by t. So my question to
所以 我们就是将这个异或结果标记为t 我对你们的问题是
you is, given the Carter-Wegman MAC pair r,t
for particular message m, how
给定计算特定消息m的carter-wegman mac值时需要的数对（r,t）
would you verify that this MAC is valid?
And recall that its algorithm V here, is
怎么核实该MAC是有效的？ 这里回忆下它的算法V
the verification algorithm for the
underlying one time MAC. So this is the
V是基础一次性MAC的认证算法 这个是正确的答案
right answer, and to see why, just observe
that this XOR here decrypts the quantity t
为了想通原因 注意这个XOR可以将数t解密成
to its plain text value, which is
basically the original underlying one time
明文值 该值是原基础一次性MAC
MAC. And so we can directly feed that into
the verification algorithm for the one
所以我们可以直接将其送入一次性MAC的认证算法
time MAC. The last type of MAC I wanted
to tell you about is one that is very
我想讨论的最后一种MAC是一种在
popular in internet protocols. It's called the HMAC. But before we talk about the HMAC we
互联网协议中非常流行的MAC 叫做HMAC 但在讨论HMAC前 我们
have to talk about hash functions and in particular, collision resistant hash
需要说明下HASH函数 尤其是 耐碰撞hash函数
functions and we are going to do that in
the next module. So this is the end of our
这些我们都将在下一模块中讨论 所以以上就是
first module on MAC-s and I wanted to point
out that there's beautiful theory that
关于MAC的第一模块内容 还有 事实上有许多很好的
went into constructing all the MAC-s that
we saw. I gave you the highlights showed
关于构建我们看到的这些MAC的理论 我已经给了你们一些展示了
you the main constructions, but
there's really quite a bit of theory that
主流构建的集锦 但确实有非常多的关于
goes into constructing these MAC-s, and if
you'd like to learn more about that, I
构建这些MAC的理论 如果你想了解更多
listed a couple of key papers you might
want to look at. Let me quickly tell you what they
我列出了你可能会想看的关键论文 让我快速做一下它们的说明
are. The first one is, what's called the
three key construction, which is the basis
第一个 称做三密钥构建 它是CMAC的基础
of CMAC. A very elegant paper that give a
very efficient construction out of CBC-MAC.
且非常精简 并给出了CBC-MAC中的一种非常有效的结构
The second paper is a more technical
paper, but basically shows how to prove
论文二技术性较高 但基本上就是关于如何证明
that bounds of CBC-MAC as a PRF. The
third paper talks about PMAC and its
做为PRF的CBC-MAC的范围 第三篇讨论了PMAC和它的结构
construction. Again, a very acute paper.
The fourth paper talks about security of
且该论文非常敏锐 第四篇讨论了
NMAC and HMAC as well. HMAC we're going to
cover in, the next module. The last paper
NMAC与HMAC的安全性 下一模块我们会涉及到HMAC 最后一篇
I listed asks an intriguing question.
Recall that all of our constructions, we
问了一个非常有趣的问题 回忆下所学的所有结构
always assume that AES is a pseudo-random
function for sixteen byte messages and we
我们一直认为AES是一供16字节长消息使用的伪随机函数
then built a pseudo-random function and
therefore a MAC for much longer messages.
所以我们构建了一伪随机函数 也构建了一供更长消息使用的MAC
This paper says well, what do we do if AES
is not a pseudo-random function, but still
该论文认为 如果AES不是伪随机函数我们该怎么办 即使如此
satisfies some weaker security property
called an unpredictable function. And then
AES依旧可以满足一些较弱的安全属性 称为不可预知功能
they ask if AES is only an unpredictable
function, but not a pseudo-random
之后该论文提出 AES是否是唯一可提供不可预测功能的算法 这里AES不是伪随机函数
function, can we still build MAC-s for long
messages? And so they succeed in actually
我们能否依旧为长消息构建MAC 之后论文成功给出
giving constructions just based on the
weaker assumption that AES is an
以AES是不可预测函数为基础的结构
unpredictable function. But their
constructions are far less sufficient than
但这个结构远不足我们在本节中讨论过的
CBC-MAC or NMAC, or PMAC that we discussed
in these segments. And so if you're
CBC-MAC、NMAC、PMAC充分 所以如果你对
interested in a different perspective on
how to build MAC-s from block ciphers like
如何以分组密码 如AES 来构建MAC的不同观点感兴趣
AES, please take a look at this paper. And
there are actually some nice open
那就请你看看这些论文 其中确实有一些与本领域相关的
questions to work on in this area. So this
concludes our first segment on integrity.
非常好的开放性问题 所以关于完整性的第一节内容就讲完了
And in the next segment, we're gonna talk
about collision resistance.
下节 我们讲讨论耐碰撞理论